<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.colinframe.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.colinframe.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-09-28T12:22:41+00:00</updated><id>https://www.colinframe.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">My Name is Colin. So what else do you need to know?</title><subtitle>Trust me, it's paradise.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Building bikes as a creative endeavour</title><link href="https://www.colinframe.com/building-bikes-as-a-creative-endeavour" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building bikes as a creative endeavour" /><published>2021-09-25T21:26:58+00:00</published><updated>2021-09-25T21:26:58+00:00</updated><id>https://www.colinframe.com/building-bikes-as-a-creative-endeavour</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.colinframe.com/building-bikes-as-a-creative-endeavour">&lt;p&gt;Anyone who knows me will know I like my bikes. I used to switch or upgrade bikes every couple of years or so. The trick to the constant upgrade cycle was to buy a supremely capable ‘adventure’ bike from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shandcycles.com/&quot;&gt;Shand Cycles&lt;/a&gt; and ride it in as many varied terrains as I could. Change the situation rather than change the bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the Shand pretty much rendering all but my commuter bike obsolete there was one itch that I yearned to scratch; restoring a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flying-scot.com&quot;&gt;Flying Scot&lt;/a&gt;. Flying Scot’s were a pre- and post-war Glaswegian bike company that specialised in ‘lightweight’ steel bikes and they were held in very high regard by all accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 5 years ago I was commuting on an old 1970’s Dutch Batavus frame which was made from Reynolds 531 steel. It was a massive step up in ride quality from the chromoly framed Dawes that I’d been running prior to that. When we had our first child however I figured I needed something a bit burlier to run a child seat and front rack on so the ‘Bat’ had to make way for a more modern disc braked Genesis single speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward another 5 years and the child seats days are numbered so the ‘classic lightweight’ itch has returned which leads me to the subject of this post - the creativity in a custom bike build.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst it could easily be seen as an excuse to pour over spec sheets and pictures of shiny bike bits I’ve come to find the process as much more of a creative endeavour. There’s an artistry in picking the right pieces to complement each other. Some group sets just look ‘right’ on one style of frame compared to another. Some modern components will blend seamlessly onto a classic frame, other scream that they’re out of place, out of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided on a ‘theme’ for my Scot build and I’m pretty sure it’s going to ruffle some feathers with those who would never look past anything other than a fully period correct restoration. I’m going modern Shimano track running gear on a frame from the 1950s and in my head it’s going to be awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch this space 🏴󠁧󠁢󠁳󠁣󠁴󠁿&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Anyone who knows me will know I like my bikes. I used to switch or upgrade bikes every couple of years or so. The trick to the constant upgrade cycle was to buy a supremely capable ‘adventure’ bike from Shand Cycles and ride it in as many varied terrains as I could. Change the situation rather than change the bike.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One year on</title><link href="https://www.colinframe.com/one-year-on" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One year on" /><published>2021-03-22T16:06:17+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-22T16:06:17+00:00</updated><id>https://www.colinframe.com/one-year-on</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.colinframe.com/one-year-on">&lt;p&gt;The same but different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title photo for this post was taken exactly one year ago on South Street in Glasgow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year on and we’re still in a Level 4 lockdown from the COVID 19 effects but if I tried to take that photo today I’d almost definitely be run down.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The same but different.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The carrot and stick of recycling</title><link href="https://www.colinframe.com/the-carrot-and-stick-of-recycling" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The carrot and stick of recycling" /><published>2021-03-11T21:54:50+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-11T21:54:50+00:00</updated><id>https://www.colinframe.com/the-carrot-and-stick-of-recycling</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.colinframe.com/the-carrot-and-stick-of-recycling">&lt;p&gt;To restrict or to educate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently my local council letter dropped our area to tell us that they were changing our bin pickup schedule - reducing general waste from a 2 weekly service to a 3 weekly service. The reasoning behind this was to ‘encourage’ residents to recycle more, apparently up to 60% of waste in the general bins is recyclable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encouraging people to recycle is a noble act, no doubt about it, but I can’t help but think that this approach - restricting other waste pickup services - is going to end up backfiring without en effort to provide more education on recycling first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city I live in isn’t very clean. Near my local area there’s a depressing amount of fly tipping, dog mess, broken glass and litter - pretty much all the time. All I can assume is that some people just don’t care about the place they call home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is with the people who don’t care that I think these changes will affect the most. There’s a good chance that if you don’t clean up after your dog you’re not going to be too bothered about recycling. If your bin starts being emptied less frequently will this encourage you to split out your recycling or just put the excess rubbish out on the street or back close? Compounding this is the fact that bulky item uplifts are now being charged for and the recycling centres are closed to all but ‘essential’ waste (what is essential waste?!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope I’m wrong and this turns things around, I really do.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="update" /><summary type="html">To restrict or to educate?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Looking for the good in lockdown</title><link href="https://www.colinframe.com/looking-for-the-good-in-lockdown" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Looking for the good in lockdown" /><published>2021-02-05T11:38:42+00:00</published><updated>2021-02-05T11:38:42+00:00</updated><id>https://www.colinframe.com/looking-for-the-good-in-lockdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.colinframe.com/looking-for-the-good-in-lockdown">&lt;p&gt;At times undoubtedly super hard but there were some bright spots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll preface this by saying that this is my personal perspective on what I experienced through the first lockdown last March. I know that for a lot of people they found it an all together much more challenging time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a society we were thrown into entirely unknown waters. I still remember running round the local neighbourhood being able to run down the middle of roads that at any other time would be permanently busy with traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;family&quot;&gt;Family&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife and I had to figure out how to juggle work and looking after our 2 young daughters who, at that point, were both still in nursery. As my job had more flexibility I would start work somewhere around 6am and bank some ‘quiet time’ to concentrate before the breakfast routine would kick off. I’d usually work till 10ish then take a couple of hours or so out to get the kids out the house and into the fresh air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was in those few hours that I found most of the goodness in lockdown. My daughters now have such a tight bond, mostly forged through having to spend so much time together over the last year - mercifully, they’re pretty good together! We’d go for picnics in the local nature walk, we rode around all the back lanes here over a few weeks, marking them off on a map as we went. They would build dens using a giant cardboard box in the house, make a cinema screening room out of a pop up tent in the garden - yes, I realise we were very lucky to have both a garden and the weather to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also found that having to split my time between them and work made me be more focussed on each ‘mode’ I was in, while I was in it. It took some doing and it’s where a good chunk of my desire to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.colinframe.com/taking-back-my-attention&quot;&gt;take back my attention&lt;/a&gt; came from. What I’m trying to do now is to keep my phone out of reach while I’m with the girls so I give them my full attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;work&quot;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having to split my days so much between work and childcare also forced me to try and be more productive when I was in a work block. Simple things like closing my email client most of the time made a big difference. I now schedule time for getting my email handled and it’s working well so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also started to work on systems to try and ‘get things done’. I’d finished reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.co.uk/Getting-Things-Done-Stress-free-Productivity/dp/0349408947&quot;&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt; sometime in 2019 which helped a lot. I’m still trying to work out exactly what the system is by writing it up in a blog post but Lockdown 3 and home schooling is kinda scuppering that at the moment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;personal&quot;&gt;Personal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I was taking a lot from spending more time with the kids I still needed some time to clear my head. To this end I made a concerted effort to get out on the bike more than in previous years. Suddenly being told that something was scarce, exercise in the case, made me realise how much I enjoyed and maybe even needed to be able to get out and pedal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The travel restrictions did curtail some of my usual routes but that just forced me to be a bit more creative. I visited a few of the Glasgow parks that I’d never been to, found an amazing loch in the Kilpatricks that I never knew existed and got to ride some dusty gravel trails in both the outskirts of Glasgow and on Arran - both of which would have given California a run for its money!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, I hope I don’t forget how getting out exploring balances my mind. My mood is better, I’m more present with Lynn &amp;amp; the kids and I feel like I’m a better person for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s all too easy to get wrapped up in the urgent and forget about the important.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">At times undoubtedly super hard but there were some bright spots.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2020 in books</title><link href="https://www.colinframe.com/2020-in-books" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2020 in books" /><published>2021-01-01T21:40:55+00:00</published><updated>2021-01-01T21:40:55+00:00</updated><id>https://www.colinframe.com/2020-in-books</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.colinframe.com/2020-in-books">&lt;p&gt;What did I read last year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time probably since becoming a parent I tried to make time to read a bit more this year. Sure it’s not huge compared to more voracious readers but it’s an improvement!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/48592299-why-we-sleep&quot;&gt;Why We Sleep: The New Science of Sleep and Dreams&lt;/a&gt; - Matthew Walker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a fascinating and very insightful read. It’s definitely got me thinking more about my sleep and trying to improve it’s quality, which has historically not been great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/21174350-essentialism&quot;&gt;Essentialism: The Disciplined Pursuit of Less&lt;/a&gt; - Greg McKeown&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago I read through a lot of minimalism books but I think Essentialism is probably more applicable to the wider public. It’s not about just throwing away all bar X number of possessions but really digging into what’s essential for you in your life, something that I think has been brought to the fore for a lot of people through the COVID-19 pandemic and associated restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18951183-the-4-hour-work-week&quot;&gt;The 4-Hour Work Week: Escape the 9-5, Live Anywhere and Join the New Rich&lt;/a&gt; - Tim Ferriss&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can see where Ferris was going with this book, empowering people to break away from the traditional 9-5 and becoming entrepreneurs but the ‘dropship’ idea in particular didn’t really sit well with me. Yes, it’s a means to your lifestyle ends but in the process it could very easily be that you’re not really providing any ‘value’ in the company that you’re building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41144788-company-of-one&quot;&gt;Company of One: Why Staying Small is the Next Big Thing for Business&lt;/a&gt; - Paul Jarvis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of the points in this book about staying small and focussing on being better rather than bigger really resonated with me. It for sure ties in with Essentialism and some of the Minimalist related books I’ve read in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/31634824-designing-your-life&quot;&gt;Designing Your Life: Build a Life that Works for You&lt;/a&gt; - Bill Burnett&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t know anything about ‘design thinking’ before reading this and I’ll be honest, I think I need to go back through it to fully solidify the idea in my mind. I also still need to go back through and go through the worksheets that it came with to help you go through the design process for your own life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54615491-atomic-habits&quot;&gt;Atomic Habits: An Easy and Proven Way to Build Good Habits and Break Bad Ones&lt;/a&gt; - James Clear&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This took me a while to get through partly because a lot of a central tenets I’d read versions of online in summaries of the book or on the authors blog. Still some useful information and tips to be had though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18600085-the-year-without-pants&quot;&gt;The Year Without Pants: WordPress.com and the Future of Work&lt;/a&gt; - Scott Berkun&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a pretty funny read and whilst it now may be a bit dated (remote work being more commonplace) it was still an interesting look into how a company like WordPress/Automattic is/was run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@itfeelslikefilm?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;🇸🇮 Janko Ferlič&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/books?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What did I read last year?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Glasgow lockdown 2.0</title><link href="https://www.colinframe.com/glasgow-lockdown-20" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glasgow lockdown 2.0" /><published>2020-11-27T21:56:11+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-27T21:56:11+00:00</updated><id>https://www.colinframe.com/glasgow-lockdown-20</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.colinframe.com/glasgow-lockdown-20">&lt;p&gt;It happened again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again Glasgow, and a large swathe of the Central Belt of Scotland has been placed into another ‘lockdown’ to try and stem the tide of COVID. On Friday 20th November we were placed into Tier 4 which is essentially the same as the lockdown conditions we faced all the way back in March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, I thought I should take a wee wander through town on the bike to see what the place ‘felt’ like this time round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I found was a little more life than previous but nothing compared to what you would expect for this time of year. That said, there were still a few glimmers of happiness to be found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/11/photo.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/11/photo-2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/11/photo-3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/11/photo-4.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/11/photo-5.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/11/photo-6.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/11/photo-7.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/11/photo-8.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/11/photo-9.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/11/photo-10.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/11/photo-11.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/11/photo-12.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/11/photo-13.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/11/photo-14.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/11/photo-15.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="update" /><summary type="html">It happened again.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Is Voice UI the way to make mobile devices ‘magical’ again?</title><link href="https://www.colinframe.com/is-voice-ui-the-way-to-make-mobile-devices-magical-again" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is Voice UI the way to make mobile devices ‘magical’ again?" /><published>2020-08-04T20:15:22+00:00</published><updated>2020-08-04T20:15:22+00:00</updated><id>https://www.colinframe.com/is-voice-ui-the-way-to-make-mobile-devices-magical-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.colinframe.com/is-voice-ui-the-way-to-make-mobile-devices-magical-again">&lt;p&gt;Could talking to our devices break their hold on our attention?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the first iPhone was released it was pitched as an ‘Internet Communications Device’. A tool to allow us to communicate in in the Internet age (email, web, IM) but still fit in our pockets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward 13 years and the modern mobile phone has become a &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/thrive-global/how-technology-hijacks-peoples-minds-from-a-magician-and-google-s-design-ethicist-56d62ef5edf3&quot;&gt;slot machine in your pocket&lt;/a&gt;. We pull out our phones and pull or swipe to refresh &lt;em&gt;just in case&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, they can also be incredible tools allowing us to perform tasks that until recently would have solely been the domain of a high powered workstation. Who hasn’t used some sort of video chat on their device through the COVID-19 pandemic over the last few months? Our family is using it pretty much daily to keep in touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, back to distractions. If we didn’t need to look at our devices, would we no longer feel so compelled to check for new notifications? Would we be less ‘worried’ by the red dots of unread notifications in so many of our apps?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaning into the Voice UI capabilities of modern smart devices might be a way to start easing ourselves away from the compulsion to check for updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has Siri, Amazon has Alexa, Samsung has Bixby, Microsoft has Cortana and Google has its assistant. Whilst none of them are perfect they’re all pretty much like science fiction compared to what existed even just a decade ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can ask your device what you want it to do without looking at the shiny screen and all the notifications maybe, just maybe, they start becoming amazing magical tools again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started using Siri more on my iPhone as a way to tell my wife I was on my bike heading home from the office and if I wanted to change what music I was listening to when I was running. Sure, I could just pull over and stop but given how often it’s raining or I’m wearing gloves, the desire to not have to stop and get the phone out of my pocket was pretty strong. These are pretty lightweight examples but it’s got me dipping my toes into what other voice commands I might be able to start using more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Could talking to our devices break their hold on our attention?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Taking back my attention - redux</title><link href="https://www.colinframe.com/taking-back-my-attention-redux" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taking back my attention - redux" /><published>2020-07-18T21:02:30+00:00</published><updated>2020-07-18T21:02:30+00:00</updated><id>https://www.colinframe.com/taking-back-my-attention-redux</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.colinframe.com/taking-back-my-attention-redux">&lt;p&gt;It feels like I’m starting to ‘win’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a month ago I decided to try and take back some of my attention from the draw of social media, Instagram and Twitter in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step I took was to block both sites on my iPhone. At first I thought I would be able to do this in the restricted sites settings (now part of Screen Time) but unfortunately this carried the restriction across all my devices - not quite what I was after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next port of call was my ad blocker. I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://1blocker.com/&quot;&gt;1Blocker&lt;/a&gt; (and highly recommend it) what has very useful custom config settings. It was a simple task to add the domains for Twitter and Instagram and boom, no more temptations. The one drawback is that I’ve had to turn off iCloud sync for the settings on my iPhone as otherwise the blocks were also spreading over to my iPad. These are the only custom rules I have so there’s no major issue there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feeling pretty chuffed with how that experiment went I took one further step: I deleted email off my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking inspiration from Tim Ferris in &lt;a href=&quot;https://fourhourworkweek.com/&quot;&gt;The 4-Hour Work Week&lt;/a&gt; I figured, why do I need to always have access to email in my pocket? Now I only do my email on my laptop or iPad and try to batch it as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I definitely find I have less of an urge to grab for my phone and play the  notification slot-machine game and am getting round to being more present in the activity I’m actually supposed to be doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next steps: could I still find the phone to be as useful tool with the browser disabled?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;background-color:black;color:white;text-decoration:none;padding:4px 6px;font-family:-apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;San Francisco&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Helvetica, Ubuntu, Roboto, Noto, &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif;font-size:12px;font-weight:bold;line-height:1.2;display:inline-block;border-radius:3px&quot; href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/ywqa9IZB-dU?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditShareLink&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; title=&quot;Download free do whatever you want high-resolution photos from rvignes&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;display:inline-block;padding:2px 3px&quot;&gt;&lt;svg xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; style=&quot;height:12px;width:auto;position:relative;vertical-align:middle;top:-2px;fill:white&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 32 32&quot;&gt;&lt;title&gt;unsplash-logo&lt;/title&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M10 9V0h12v9H10zm12 5h10v18H0V14h10v9h12v-9z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;display:inline-block;padding:2px 3px&quot;&gt;rvignes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="update" /><summary type="html">It feels like I’m starting to ‘win’.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Taking back my attention</title><link href="https://www.colinframe.com/taking-back-my-attention" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Taking back my attention" /><published>2020-06-09T21:41:30+00:00</published><updated>2020-06-09T21:41:30+00:00</updated><id>https://www.colinframe.com/taking-back-my-attention</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.colinframe.com/taking-back-my-attention">&lt;p&gt;An experiment in intentionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I last setup my iPhone I deliberately didn’t install the Instagram app. I’d already largely sworn off Twitter and ditched using my Facebook account completely after the birth of our first child. My FB account still exists though, more on that in another post. Instagram was, and, to a degree, still is a big source of distraction for me. It’s so easy to just hop on and have a quick scroll through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, what I’m not doing is going on a cold turkey social media detox. I’ve found in recent weeks that Instagram and Twitter can be legitimately useful. A few weeks ago I found a new place to ride out to on the bike that I might not have considered had I not seen someone else’s Instagram post about it. I did, I rode there and it really was a fantastic wee spot less then 10 miles away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with the native app not installed it’s so easy to just open up the web app - which is very very good these days. I find myself with a few short minutes of ‘downtime’, pop open Safari, have a mindless scroll, try to go back to what I was doing before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’m trying this time is to block both Instagram and Twitter via the content restrictions in iOS 13 on my iPhone. I’m not giving up on them completely, I’m just forcing myself to use my laptop or iPad to access them. They’re not always right by me so I’ll hopefully be a bit more mindful and intentional about how and when I use the services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll update in a while to follow up on how the ‘experiment’ has gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should also say I’m far from being the first to try or advocate such an experiment. I’m taking a lot of cues from (in no particular order) &lt;a href=&quot;https://maketime.blog/article/the-distraction-free-iphone/&quot;&gt;Make Time&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://humanetech.com/resources/take-control/&quot;&gt;Centre for Humane Technology&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.calnewport.com/blog/2017/10/02/are-you-using-social-media-or-being-used-by-it/&quot;&gt;Cal Newport&lt;/a&gt; and plenty more I’m probably forgetting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;background-color:black;color:white;text-decoration:none;padding:4px 6px;font-family:-apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &amp;quot;San Francisco&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Helvetica, Ubuntu, Roboto, Noto, &amp;quot;Segoe UI&amp;quot;, Arial, sans-serif;font-size:12px;font-weight:bold;line-height:1.2;display:inline-block;border-radius:3px&quot; href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@freestocks?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; title=&quot;Download free do whatever you want high-resolution photos from freestocks&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;display:inline-block;padding:2px 3px&quot;&gt;&lt;svg xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; style=&quot;height:12px;width:auto;position:relative;vertical-align:middle;top:-2px;fill:white&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 32 32&quot;&gt;&lt;title&gt;unsplash-logo&lt;/title&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M10 9V0h12v9H10zm12 5h10v18H0V14h10v9h12v-9z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;display:inline-block;padding:2px 3px&quot;&gt;freestocks&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="update" /><summary type="html">An experiment in intentionality.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The ‘uncanny valley’ of Glasgow during Corona</title><link href="https://www.colinframe.com/the-uncanny-valley-of-glasgow-during-corona" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The ‘uncanny valley’ of Glasgow during Corona" /><published>2020-03-31T16:10:30+00:00</published><updated>2020-03-31T16:10:30+00:00</updated><id>https://www.colinframe.com/the-uncanny-valley-of-glasgow-during-corona</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.colinframe.com/the-uncanny-valley-of-glasgow-during-corona">&lt;p&gt;These are unprecedented times indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Times we will be telling kids and grandkids about in decades to come. With that in mind I wanted to get some documentation of the centre of Glasgow. Not for any morbid reason - purely to have seen it with my own eyes and to be able to show it to the girls when they’re old enough to really understand what was going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I described what I saw to one of my friends as almost an ‘uncanny valley’ version of Glasgow, almost right but something was just a bit off. The lack of people hustling and bustling about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The photos I grabbed aren’t the best but I was conscious of not wanting to appear reckless in my exercise time (I was out on the bike doing the sub ride, more on that another time)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/03/IMG_2290.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/03/IMG_2291.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/03/IMG_2293.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/03/IMG_2296.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/03/IMG_2299.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/03/IMG_2301.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/03/IMG_2305.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/03/IMG_2307.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2020/03/IMG_2318.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="update" /><summary type="html">These are unprecedented times indeed.</summary></entry></feed>